<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Edification by chance</title>
  <subtitle>intriguing reading habbits</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://www.educhant.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-07-10T21:29:58.200Z</updated>
  <id>http://www.educhant.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Pradeep Kumar Sharma</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ignore if corrected ...</title>
    <link href="http://www.educhant.com/2016/07/11/Ignore-if-corrected/"/>
    <id>http://www.educhant.com/2016/07/11/Ignore-if-corrected/</id>
    <published>2016-07-11T02:53:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-10T21:29:58.200Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was taking a sip in the balcony of my first floor residential quarter in the evening. This is the complex of four blocks of 8 quarters surrounding one square lawn. In the lawn benches are placed for lounging. The moment I witnessed one of my fellow instructor talking on phone with his daughter who is 2nd grader. He had the opportunity to join as trainee instructor in the institution meant for the clerks. At the mean time one of my colleagues joined me jovially entering the room. We just has our gossips that we concentrated on the fluctuating discourse of the whitish strong built seems to be educated fellow. We kept mum and listened to the explanation and direction being given to his daughter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His daughter was assigned home work to write one paragraph on the topic ‘Drought’. He mentioned with full authenticity that where there is heavy rain and flood like condition is known as draught. Actually he was explaining the difficult words, perhaps making her write that this word came in follow through. Our notice was all about that he is a good father that besides being away for the time being he is providing every help and assistance to he daughter in her school activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were shun after listening his argument but did not interfere him of being scared. However the gesture that embodies it looked as if he was wrong somewhere. The next day I and my friend were amused to see his in front of the class room meant to teach grammar. It stopped only when we indicated him to understand the correct meaning of ‘Drought’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The education is life long process. It continues from cradle to pyre. Today formal and informal education features in almost all the societies. The world of knowledge has expended. There have been numerous sources of acquiring knowledge and is easily accessible too. The minds today is well equipped with sophisticated fields. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To shy and hide the ignorance may lead to the dark arena of knowledge. The act father did will not simply be forgotten as the child in her environment will definitely come to know by leaving no space to sorry. Chances are you being hated against teachers trust. Also the conflict in mind will abstract the space of right knowledge and may have no chance to take help of digital dictionary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The society which allowed us to come across such situation where we could not directly interfere in his on line tuition there needs more openness and close contacts for the persons in the world of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;I was taking a sip in the balcony of my first floor residential quarter in the evening. This is the complex of four blocks of 8 quarters surrounding one square lawn.&lt;br&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="tips" scheme="http://www.educhant.com/tags/tips/"/>
    
      <category term="life" scheme="http://www.educhant.com/tags/life/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dropping-out water</title>
    <link href="http://www.educhant.com/2016/07/09/Dropping-out-water/"/>
    <id>http://www.educhant.com/2016/07/09/Dropping-out-water/</id>
    <published>2016-07-09T15:01:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-13T17:18:17.594Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its long after I visited my home in scorching summer this year in country side. Several years back there were greenrees in this season which is not visible today. I witnessed wells, ponds and nearby river running out of water. The practice of houling drinking water is over now and people use handpumps and tubewells for usage of water. This is depend on the availability of electricity. Any way they are used to in storing and managing water. Some times usually in night wild animals hover around the houses in search of water. Still today, sorrounding my home, grooves of tall trees/orchards of mangoes,blue berry, peepal, neem and other shedy trees can be seen under which herds of cattle settle during hot summer days along with herders. They wait for the Sun to alight before they spread around for grazing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The climatic change if I would be right to mention has an impetus on the habitat of the region as people are rationally involved in their practice of utilizing water as they used to do long back. The abundance of water reserves went scarce only to the climatic change. People are adapted with the changing situations. It seems as if they are not worried. This phenamenon at large scale may lead to the drought and starvation. Which I witnessed at one village can be the scene of large populated areas which in turn may take tough managerial practice by the governments itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since in the cities use of water is minimal and is limited to their day today use for bathing cleaning etc. Factories use and recycle waste water. People hardly find any kitchen garden to irrigate but the eco friendly people decorate their flower pots. However in the villages cultivating field and crops need lot of water. If its done the season, the need of extra is over. However with the spreading awareness agriculturists are more alert. Even then use of no proper water nullas/pipes and percolating water waste at some extent is concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human practice is also is the scene in villages where people install pucca treches filled with water for stray animals and birds. May God live with them ! We have also the sope of spreading awareness with the world pacing fast in technology. And communicate living with them in global village. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Its long after I visited my home in scorching summer this year in country side. Several years back there were greenrees in this season which is not visible today.&lt;br&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="discovery" scheme="http://www.educhant.com/tags/discovery/"/>
    
      <category term="enlightment" scheme="http://www.educhant.com/tags/enlightment/"/>
    
      <category term="travel" scheme="http://www.educhant.com/tags/travel/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tips to adapting to a new situation</title>
    <link href="http://www.educhant.com/2016/07/08/Tips-to-Adapting-to-a-new-situation/"/>
    <id>http://www.educhant.com/2016/07/08/Tips-to-Adapting-to-a-new-situation/</id>
    <published>2016-07-08T03:08:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-09T10:21:40.521Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you shy of adjusting and adapting to a new situation? Here are tips that would find you in the realm of adjusted world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding the environment that lead to a new situation will be helpful a lot in managing you adjust to a new one. Time to come is the world of opportunities and we without knowing the future action involve in the situations to adjust. A successful person is one who has dynamically calculated the methodology to adapt with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Past experienced play a role. Your family, surroundings and the field you are working with have definitely added to your adjustment in the new situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing resources available provide you to settle down well with the situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turnout and bearing proves to be fruitful in finding a person settled. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language and style of of conversation have a role to play in different social atmosphere. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge in particular field have a wise effect on the movements of personal adjustment. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical skills also apply to manoeuvre with the situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiar people, peer group or the place already visited the like location or situation are the best guides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Are you shy of adjusting and adapting to a new situation? Here are tips that would find you in the realm of adjusted world&lt;br&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="lifehacks" scheme="http://www.educhant.com/tags/lifehacks/"/>
    
      <category term="tips" scheme="http://www.educhant.com/tags/tips/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
